

 $\label{eq:composition} \begin{tabular}{ll} $\boxtimes$ xiangli4job@gmail.com & & xiangli.work \\ For up-to-date version and other contacts, please visit http://xiangli.work \\ \end{tabular}$ 

I'm an iOS engineer with 2.5+ years experience. I've built 4 apps with 14+ upgrades on App Store. Authorized to work in the US.

## **Work Experience**

iOS Engineer Mountain View, CA

Yttro Mobile

February 2015 - Present

- Published Yttro for iOS version 1.0 to App Store from nearly scratch in 3 months as sole full-time iOS Engineer. Unfortunately it's removed by Apple a few months later.
- Helped build H5 version, helped coordinate on UX/UI, Android, backend, etc.

iOS Developer

Beijing, China / Stanford, CA

June 2013 - January 2015

Solopreneur

- Published 3 indie apps and 13 updates to App Store.
- The one I love most is "Artisan's Workshop" (http://xiangli.work/#apps). I hope young people open their minds and think independently by reading what my friends and I share to them, then achieve their goals by actual practice. These features are all in this app. It contains reading, a built-in PDCA (plan-do-check-adjust) cycle, reminders, statistics, notes, etc..
- Skills trained: mobile product design, architect, development, distribution, marketing, ASO, CRM, etc.

**Product Manager** 

Beijing, China

Baidu, Inc. October 2011 – May 2013

- PM of Pulse, a BI alike product for decision makers (CEO/CFO, E-staff, GMs) in Baidu. 4 PMs lead and coorporated with 20+ divisions, covered 300+ operational indicators, launched version 1.0 successfully within 3 months, and 12 upgrades afterwards.
- Skills trained: requirement management, product design, MRD & roadmap development, coordinate UE(UX/UI)/FE/RD/QA to meet the goals on roadmap, scrum practice over 1 year.

Intern, Software Engineer, Tech Lead China Railway Signal & Communication Co.

BJ, China / Braunschweig, Germany / Hassleholm, Sweden

July 2007 - October 2011

- Co-inventor & chief software engineer for TSRS (Temporary Speed Restriction System), one of the vital equipments of CTCS-3 (Chinese Train Control System level 3). Adapted TSRS perfectly to 6 high-speed railway lines of great importance to China, such as Beijing-Shanghai, Wuhan-Guangzhou, etc. Worked hard day and night, received lots of honors & awards.
- Skills trained: C, Unix/Linux, SVN, SIL4 (Highest standard of safety), Fail-Safe computing platform & application software.
- Patents: CN102267477B (Grant, Temporary speed restriction command management equipment of CTCS-3 system)

## **Education**

Tsinghua University

Beijing, China

 $BE\ \&\ ME,\ Automation.\ Field\ of\ research:\ Intelligent\ Transportation\ System.$ 

August 2002 – February 2009

- 1st of Jilin province (over 100k competitors) in The National College Entrance Examination
- Siyuan program scholarship (30 out of 3k students)

## **Technical and Personal skills**

- o Programming Languages: Objective C, Swift, Javascript/jQuery/Node.js/React.js, HTML(5)/CSS(3), Ruby on Rails.
- o iOS Knowledge Keywords: Storyboard/Xib/Code, Autolayout, Multithreading/GCD, Core Data, File System, Networking, Background fetches, Core Location/MapKit, Core Motion, Core Graphics, Core Animation, Gestures, Local Notifications, IAP, ARC, etc. Third party: Evernote-SDK, WeChat-SDK, AFNetworking, JSONKit, HighChart, PNChart, SDWebImage, FileHash, iRate, HtmlUnescape, WebP image process, Zip/Unzip, Gif Player, StatusBar Notification, Calendars, Mixpanel/Flurry, etc.
- o Language: Mandarin (native), English (limited working proficiency, ILR Level 2).
- Other: Love running & sunshine. Extreme hardworking. Love to keep up with the latest technologies, best practices and techniques, learn new things, expand my comfort zone, and build things with craftsman's spirit.